<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/4/2016 2:00:14 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--Elder Council-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ELDER_COUNCIL">
			<Text>Elder Council</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ELDER_COUNCIL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Elder councils grant an early science boost by generating 1 [ICON_SCIENCE] Science.  Obsolete with Education.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDINGS_ELDER_COUNCIL_DESC">
			<Text>
				Oral tradition, oral culture and oral lore are messages or testimony transmitted orally from one generation to another.  The messages or testimony are verbally transmitted in speech or song and may take the form, for example, of folktales, sayings, ballads, songs, or chants. In this way, it is possible for a society to transmit oral history, oral literature, oral law and other knowledges across generations without a writing system.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ELDER_COUNCIL_HELP">
			<Text>
				Early science building.  Obsolete with Education.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Furrier-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER">
			<Text>Furrier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDINGS_FURRIER_DESC">
			<Text>
				Fur is generally thought to have been among the first materials used for clothing and bodily decoration. The exact date when fur was first used in clothing is debated. It is known that several species of hominoids including Homo sapiens and Homo neanderthalensis used fur clothing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fur is still worn in most mild and cool climates around the world due to its superior warmth and durability. From the days of early European settlement, up until the development of modern clothing alternatives, fur clothing was popular in Canada during the cold winters. The invention of inexpensive synthetic textiles for insulating clothing led to fur clothing falling out of fashion.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fur is still used by indigenous people and developed societies, due to its availability and superior insulation properties. The Inuit peoples of the Arctic relied on fur for most of their clothing, and it also forms a part of traditional clothing in Russia, Ukraine, Yugoslavia, Scandinavia, and Japan.  It is also sometimes associated with glamour and lavish spending. A number of consumers and designers—notably British fashion designer and outspoken animal rights activist Stella McCartney—reject fur due to moral beliefs and perceived cruelty to animals.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Animal furs used in garments and trim may be dyed bright colors or with patterns, often to mimic exotic animal pelts: alternatively they may be left their original pattern and color. Fur may be shorn down to imitate the feel of velvet, creating a fabric called shearling.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Furriers can only be constructed in a city near to one or more improved [ICON_RES_DEER] deer, [ICON_RES_FUR] fur, [ICON_RES_BISON] bison or [ICON_RES_SHEEP ] sheep.  Furriers will generate an extra 1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold for those resources.  Furrier also increases a civilization's [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FURRIER_HELP">
			<Text>
				Each source of [ICON_RES_DEER] Deer, [ICON_RES_FUR] Fur,  [ICON_RES_BISON] Bison and [ICON_RES_SHEEP] Sheep produce an extra 1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold.  [NEWLINE]City must have an improved source of Deer, Fur, Bison or Sheep nearby.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Lascaux Caves-->		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LASCAUX_CAVES_WONDER_TITLE">
			<Text>Lascaux Caves</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LASCAUX_CAVES_CIVILOPEDIA">
			<Text>Lascaux Caves is the setting of a complex of caves in southwestern France famous for its Paleolithic cave paintings. The original caves are located near the village of Montignac, in the department of Dordogne. They contain some of the best-known Upper Paleolithic art. These paintings are estimated to be circa 17,300 years old.  They primarily consist of images of large animals, most of which are known from fossil evidence to have lived in the area at the time. In 1979, Lascaux was added to the UNESCO World Heritage Sites list along with other prehistoric sites in the Vézère valley.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The cave contains nearly 2,000 figures, which can be grouped into three main categories: animals, human figures, and abstract signs.  Most of the major images have been painted onto the walls using red, yellow, and black colours from a complex multiplicity of mineral pigments including iron compounds such as iron oxide (ochre) haematite, and goethite, as well as manganese-containing pigments.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LASCAUX_CAVES_WONDER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Lascaux Caves can only be constructed in a city near to one or more [ICON_RES_DEER] deer, [ICON_RES_BISON] Bison, [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horse, [ICON_RES_COW] Cattle or [ICON_RES_IVORY] Ivory.  Lascaux Caves will generate an extra 1 [ICON_FAITH] Faith for those resources in the city where its built.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LASCAUX_CAVES_WONDER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The animals will emerge out of darkness as you pass. Nothing stays still. Shadows nestle in the cavities; a flicker of light across pale protruding rock turns a hoof or raises a head. One shape recedes as another emerges, and everything lingers in the imagination."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] — Jane Brox, Brilliant: The Evolution of Artificial Light[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LASCAUX_CAVES_WONDER_HELP">
			<Text>1 [ICON_PEACE] faith for each [ICON_RES_DEER] Deer, [ICON_RES_BISON] Bison, [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horse, [ICON_RES_COW] Cattle and [ICON_RES_IVORY] Ivory.  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a source of Deer, Bison, Horse, Cattle or Ivory nearby.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Knossoss-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_KNOSSOS_WONDER_TITLE">
			<Text>Labyrinth of Knossos</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_KNOSSOS_CIVILOPEDIA">
			<Text>In Greek mythology, the labyrinth of knossos was an elaborate structure designed and built by the legendary artificer Daedalus for King Minos of Crete at Knossos. Its function was to hold the Minotaur eventually killed by the hero Theseus. Daedalus had so cunningly made the Labyrinth that he could barely escape it after he built it.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Although early Cretan coins occasionally exhibit branching (multicursal) patterns, the single-path (unicursal) seven-course "Classical" design without branching or dead ends became associated with the Labyrinth on coins as early as 430 BC, and similar non-branching patterns became widely used as visual representations of the Labyrinth – even though both logic and literary descriptions make it clear that the Minotaur was trapped in a complex branching maze. Even as the designs became more elaborate, visual depictions of the mythological Labyrinth from Roman times until the Renaissance are almost invariably unicursal. Branching mazes were reintroduced only when garden mazes became popular during the Renaissance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_KNOSSOS_WONDER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Enemy units take damage if they move or end their turn within 2 tiles of the city where its built.  Also provides an early defense boost.  Requires [ICON_RES_STONE] stone in city vicinity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_KNOSSOS_WONDER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"There is no great invention, from fire to flying, which has not been hailed as an insult to some god."</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_KNOSSOS_HELP">
			<Text>Enemy units take 10 damage if they move or end their turn within 2 tiles of the city.  Increases city defense strength by 5 and Hit Points by 25.  Obsolete with dynamite.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<!--Carpenter-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CARPENTER">
			<Text>Carpenter</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CARPENTER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				The Carpenter building grants a 10% building [PRODUCTION] Production boost.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDINGS_CARPENTER_DESC">
			<Text>
				Wood is one of mankind's oldest building materials. The ability to shape wood improved with technological advances from the stone age to the bronze age to the iron age. Some of the oldest archaeological evidence of carpentry are water well casings built using split oak timbers with mortise and tenon and notched corners excavated in eastern Germany dating from about 7,000 years ago in the early neolithic period.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Some of the oldest, surviving, wooden buildings in the world are the temples in China such as the Nanchan Temple built in the year 782, the Greensted Church parts of which are from the 11th century, the stave churchs in Norway from the 12th and 13th centuries.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CARPENTER_HELP">
			<Text>
				10% [PRODUCTION] Production when constructing buildings.
			</Text>
		</Row>


		<!--Fish Traps-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_TRAPS">
			<Text>Fish Traps</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_TRAPS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Fish traps can only be constructed in a city near one or more [ICON_RES_FISH] fish or [ICON_RES_CRAB] crab.  Fish traps will generate an extra 1 [ICON_FOOD] Food for those resources.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDINGS_FISH_TRAPS_DESC">
			<Text>
				A fish trap is a trap used for fishing. Fish traps may have the form of a fishing wire or a lobster trap. A typical trap might consist of a frame of thick steel wire in the shape of a heart, with chicken wire stretched around it. The mesh wraps around the frame and then tapers into the inside of the trap. When a fish swims inside through this opening, it cannot get out, as the chicken wire opening bends back into its original narrowness. In earlier times, traps were constructed of wood and fibre.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fish Traps are culturally almost universal and seem to have been independently invented many times. There are essentially two types of trap, a permanent or semi-permanent structure placed in a river or tidal area and bottle or pot trap that are usually, but not always baited to attract prey, and are periodically lifted out of the water.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FISH_TRAPS_HELP">
			<Text>
				Each source of [ICON_RES_FISH] Fish and [ICON_RES_CRAB] Crab produce an extra 1 [ICON_FOOD] Food.  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must have a source of Fish or Crab nearby.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Apiary-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APIARY">
			<Text>Apiary</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APIARY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				An Apiary will generate an extra 1 [ICON_FOOD] Food and 1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDINGS_APIARY_DESC">
			<Text>
				Beekeeping (or apiculture) is the maintenance of honey bee colonies, commonly in man-made hives, by humans. A beekeeper (or apiarist) keeps bees in order to collect their honey and other products that the hive produces (including beeswax, propolis, pollen, and royal jelly), to pollinate crops, or to produce bees for sale to other beekeepers. A location where bees are kept is called an apiary or bee yard.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APIARY_HELP">
			<Text>
				Provides a small gold and science boost.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Palisade-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE">
			<Text>
				Palisade
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE_TEXT">
			<Text>
				A palisade (sometimes called a stakewall) is typically a fence or wall made from wooden stakes or tree trunks and used as a defensive structure.
				Typical construction consisted of small or mid sized tree trunks aligned vertically, with no spacing in between. The trunks were sharpened or pointed at the top, and were driven into the ground and were sometimes reinforced with additional construction. The height of a palisade ranged from a few feet to nearly ten feet. As a defensive structure, palisades were often used in conjunction with earthworks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Palisades were an excellent option for small forts or other hastily constructed fortifications. Since they were wood, they could be quickly and easily built from materials readily available. They proved to be effective protection for short-term conflicts, and were an effective deterrent against small forces. However, due to their wooden construction, they were also vulnerable to fire and siege weapons.
				Often, a palisade would be constructed around a castle as a temporary wall until a permanent stone wall could be erected. They were frequently used in New France.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Provides the city with a small defense bonus.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALISADE_HELP">
			<Text>
				Provides the city with a small defense bonus.  Obsolete with Gunpowder.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Fire pit-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FIRE_PIT">
			<Text>
				Fire Pit
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FIRE_PIT_TEXT">
			<Text>
				Many cultures, particularly nomadic ones would cut the turf above the fire-pit in a turf cutting ceremony, replacing the turf afterwards to hide any evidence of the fire. Elements of this ceremony remain in traditional youth organizations such as the Woodcraft Folk.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FIRE_PIT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>
				Provides the city with a small culture boost.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FIRE_PIT_HELP">
			<Text>
				Provides the city with a small culture boost.  Obsolete with Philosophy.
			</Text>
		</Row>


	</Language_en_US>

</GameData>